Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Executive Assistant, Mabel Bright FA220
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Executive Assistant, Mabel Bright
1963-1984
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Bright, Mabel
Rockefeller University
FA220
0.2 Cubic Feet 1 box
1 box.
Biographical/Historical note
Mabel Bright served as Dr. Detlev W. Bronk's executive assistant. Having come originally to the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (RIMR) as a part-time secretary, she became Bronk's administrative assistant in 1954. Since 1959, Ms. Bright also served as the assistant secretary to the Board of Trustees. She retired in 1976.
Scope and Contents note
Includes correspondence and biographical material on RU president, Detlev W. Bronk.
Correspondents include Britton Chance.
Subjects include Detlev W. Bronk and the National Academy of Sciences - Centennial Celebration.
Arrangement note
Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 320
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for scholarly research.
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Bright, Mabel; Rockefeller University; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.)
- American Philosophical Society's Biographical Memoirs of Detlev W. Bronk, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - General, 1967 1977 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - Letters of Condolence on the Death of Detlev W. Bronk, A-C, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence - Letters of Condolence on the Death of Detlev W. Bronk, D-P, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Letters of Condolence on the Death of Detlev W. Bronk, R-W, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Greetings to Mabel Bright from Graduates of the Rockefeller Institute and the Rockefeller University, 1959-1971 1977 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Memorial Prayer - Helen Bronk, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Memorial Resolutions - Detlev W. Bronk, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- National Academy of Sciences - Centennial Celebration, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research History - Anecdotes about Mabel Bright, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)